<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello_world</title>
    <link>https://jamied.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello_world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 12:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamied.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to a headless Raspberry Pi without a network</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2022/05/connecting-to-a-headless-raspberry-pi-without-a-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2022/05/connecting-to-a-headless-raspberry-pi-without-a-network/</guid>
      <description>When travelling, connecting to a Raspberry Pi can be problematic if you there is no wifi or a shared network available. I discovered this trick a few years ago whilst stuck in an airport lounge, and have been meaning to blog it for my future self. Until, a couple of weeks ago I faced the same challenge in an office where there was no network, or means to connect a headless RPi and debug some Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tamiya Wild Willy WR02 - Lockdown project</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/04/tamiya-wild-willy-wr02-lockdown-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/04/tamiya-wild-willy-wr02-lockdown-project/</guid>
      <description>During lockdown I wanted something to do that didn&amp;rsquo;t involve a computer screen as I was spending crazy hours at the keyboard. I&amp;rsquo;ve (literally) home automated the shit out of my house already, so instead, returned to an old childhood hobby. As a kid I loved building and racing Tamiya RC cars, my first one was the entry level Tamiya Falcon, I then worked my way through some of their models with the Tamiya Hotshot being one of my favourites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with multiple browser profiles</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/working-with-multiple-browser-profiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 19:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/working-with-multiple-browser-profiles/</guid>
      <description>Now that Edge (chromium) is so damn good on Windows I use only one browser, but manage multiple profiles within it. So I have profiles for work, personal and customer projects. I can then open a dedicated browser within each profile and be working purely in that context keeping me productive.
One thing you might like to do is create a shortcut to a specific browser profile. With a browser profile already running you can select the Pin to taskbar option by right clicking on the running browser here:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving Lockdown</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/saving-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 20:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/saving-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>Emergency surgery on the Xbox Kinect Phew! Tonight I saved lockdown in our household by fixing the Xbox Kinect :) Not many people seam to care or use the Kinect anymore, it was ahead of it&amp;rsquo;s time and never really got the traction it deserved. However, Just Dance 2021 (and previous versions) still supports it on the Xbox One.
Just Dance screen time is one I don&amp;rsquo;t mind the kids having, I&amp;rsquo;m an ex-breaker, so always happy to encourage dancing and listening to music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikea Tradfri switch hack</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/ikea-tradfri-switch-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 18:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/ikea-tradfri-switch-hack/</guid>
      <description>Here I&amp;rsquo;m modifying an Ikea Tradfri Wireless Dimmer switch, one of the cheapest Zigbee buttons on the market at £6, into an industrial mechanical switch.
I wanted a rugged button to control some smart home devices, the Fibaro The Button, whilst looks great, IMHO it&amp;rsquo;s over priced at nearly £50. This post looks to create a much cheaper alternative and have some fun with a soldering iron along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Nest SmartThings Integration</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/google-nest-smartthings-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/google-nest-smartthings-integration/</guid>
      <description>Google Nest is now officially supported on SmartThings, until now I&amp;rsquo;d been using the awesome Nest Manager by Tonesto7 - but decided to take the plunge and see what this new integration looks like.
This blog takes you through the process of migrating your Nest account over to Google Nest, then integrating any Nest devices you have into your SmartThings environment. The process is easy, but long winded, it&amp;rsquo;s also irreversible, so this will show you what to expect during the SmartThings migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Home Multiplayer Bomb Disposal Game / Escape Room</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 20:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</guid>
      <description>About 18 months ago I shared some insight into some home automation I&amp;rsquo;d added that turned the whole house into a gaming zone. This has been pretty useful during the recent covid lockdown and provided much entertainment for the family. This post is to explain how it works.
Game objective Find and defuse the bomb without getting spotted. A baddie has hidden a bomb somewhere around the house, the bomb disposal team have been sent in to locate and defuse it - without activating any of the movement or contact sensors around the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting ARM DeploymentScripts</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/troubleshooting-arm-deploymentscripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 15:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/troubleshooting-arm-deploymentscripts/</guid>
      <description>The new ARM resource type Microsoft.Resources/deploymentScripts allows you to execute scripts within template deployments, capture the script outputs and re-use them later within the rest of the template.
Whilst the documentation goes some way to help you monitor and troubleshoot when the script doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as planned using the provided script service storage accounts, out of the box,I didn&amp;rsquo;t find these particularly helpful to identify why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting the required outputs from my inline bash script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Webhooks With Azure Functions and SmartThings</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/08/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions-and-smartthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 19:54:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/08/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions-and-smartthings/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I saw Martin WoodWard&amp;rsquo;s Brian the Build Bunny for Team Foundation Server over 12 years ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by creating signals for continuous integration builds. Following on from my last post, where I walk through creating and setting up a GitHub Webhook with Azure Functions, the next logical step was to integrate this to SmartThings for complete home automation.
SmartThings has a new REST API, which I&amp;rsquo;ve created and released a SmartThings NET library, which gives you the ability to interrogate your SmartThings home automation ecosystem entirely using dotnet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Webhooks With Azure Functions</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/07/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:50:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/07/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wanted to build a GitHub webhook using C# Azure Functions, but could only find an example template using Node.js. Here, I set out to create a webhook to check the overall status of a build. This is something I was doing around 10 years ago with Team Foundation Server, so thought it would be fun to get this up and running with GitHub Actions.
Check Suites Looking at the available webhook events there wasn&amp;rsquo;t an obvious event I could subscribe to get what I wanted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>