<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello_world</title>
    <link>https://jamied.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Hello_world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 20:08:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamied.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulumi Azure Bot Service</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/pulumi-azure-bot-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 20:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/pulumi-azure-bot-service/</guid>
      <description>Pulumi IaaC =&amp;gt; IaaC# (Infrastructure as CSharp) - Deploying Azure bots with Pulumi I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that, until a week ago, I had never heard of Pulumi, but when they recently announced support for .NET - they got my attention. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked alot with JSON based Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates in the past - but these quickly become complicated to author when you have many different Azure resources.
Terraform offers it&amp;rsquo;s own HashiCorp Configuration Language (HCL), but whenever I look at any examples a bit of me wants to die - what is this strange syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Direct Line Speech</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/10/direct-line-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/10/direct-line-speech/</guid>
      <description>Anne Uumellmahaye voice bot using Azure Bot Service: Direct Line Speech Recreating Anne Uumellmahaye using AI from the film The Man with Two Brains. Spooktacular fun with the Azure Bot Service using the Direct Line Speech channel and the Microsoft Cognitive Speech SDK.
Architecture Technologies used  Azure Bot Service and Direct Line Channel Bot Framework Microsoft Cognitive Services  Dispatcher LUIS QnA Maker Speech SDK  Azure Functions Spotify API UWP Raspberry Pi running Windows 10 IoT Halloween head  Who&amp;rsquo;s Freddy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Automation</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/05/home-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 19:49:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/05/home-automation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting/playing with home automation for a while now, specifically SmartThings and their development environment. At first I was overwhelmed by it all as it seemed a steep learning curve, getting to grips with the Groovy IDE and terminology such as device handlers and SmartApps - but now it&amp;rsquo;s a labour of love.
First things first though, home automation is largely pointless, it&amp;rsquo;s un-necessary and will likely cause you more problems that it&amp;rsquo;s worth in the short term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/about/</guid>
      <description>-- I work as a Software Developer Engineer within Microsoft Commercial Software Engineering, helping customers and partners develop solutions based on the Microsoft Azure platform. I&amp;rsquo;m as old as I look, with over 20 years’ experience as a Microsoft software developer. I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about the Intelligent Cloud and creating new experiences using a range of Microsoft technologies. I have a degree from the university of life and once read some books (I also have a real degree, but have learn&amp;rsquo;t far more from real industry experience).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credits</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/credits/</guid>
      <description>This site is powered by Hugo and uses a slightly tweaked version of the Hello Friend NG Theme by rhazdon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Home</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/04/new-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 16:44:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/04/new-home/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved my online home from https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton to here. Moving my site to Hugo using a static content builder will hopefully mean that I can blog more often, and now that I&amp;rsquo;m outside the blogs.msdn.microsoft.com domain I can write and share other technical articles or things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with.
So speaking of which, leads me to my upcoming next post about Home Automation&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>