<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>smarthome on Hello_world</title>
    <link>https://jamied.me/tags/smarthome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in smarthome on Hello_world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 18:20:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamied.me/tags/smarthome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ikea Tradfri switch hack</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/ikea-tradfri-switch-hack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 18:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/ikea-tradfri-switch-hack/</guid>
      <description>Here I&amp;rsquo;m modifying an Ikea Tradfri Wireless Dimmer switch, one of the cheapest Zigbee buttons on the market at £6, into an industrial mechanical switch.
I wanted a rugged button to control some smart home devices, the Fibaro The Button, whilst looks great, IMHO it&amp;rsquo;s over priced at nearly £50. This post looks to create a much cheaper alternative and have some fun with a soldering iron along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Nest SmartThings Integration</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/google-nest-smartthings-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/google-nest-smartthings-integration/</guid>
      <description>Google Nest is now officially supported on SmartThings, until now I&amp;rsquo;d been using the awesome Nest Manager by Tonesto7 - but decided to take the plunge and see what this new integration looks like.
This blog takes you through the process of migrating your Nest account over to Google Nest, then integrating any Nest devices you have into your SmartThings environment. The process is easy, but long winded, it&amp;rsquo;s also irreversible, so this will show you what to expect during the SmartThings migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Home Multiplayer Bomb Disposal Game / Escape Room</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 20:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</guid>
      <description>About 18 months ago I shared some insight into some home automation I&amp;rsquo;d added that turned the whole house into a gaming zone. This has been pretty useful during the recent covid lockdown and provided much entertainment for the family. This post is to explain how it works.
Game objective Find and defuse the bomb without getting spotted. A baddie has hidden a bomb somewhere around the house, the bomb disposal team have been sent in to locate and defuse it - without activating any of the movement or contact sensors around the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Webhooks With Azure Functions and SmartThings</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/08/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions-and-smartthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 19:54:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/08/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions-and-smartthings/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I saw Martin WoodWard&amp;rsquo;s Brian the Build Bunny for Team Foundation Server over 12 years ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by creating signals for continuous integration builds. Following on from my last post, where I walk through creating and setting up a GitHub Webhook with Azure Functions, the next logical step was to integrate this to SmartThings for complete home automation.
SmartThings has a new REST API, which I&amp;rsquo;ve created and released a SmartThings NET library, which gives you the ability to interrogate your SmartThings home automation ecosystem entirely using dotnet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Automation</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/05/home-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 19:49:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/05/home-automation/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting/playing with home automation for a while now, specifically SmartThings and their development environment. At first I was overwhelmed by it all as it seemed a steep learning curve, getting to grips with the Groovy IDE and terminology such as device handlers and SmartApps - but now it&amp;rsquo;s a labour of love.
First things first though, home automation is largely pointless, it&amp;rsquo;s un-necessary and will likely cause you more problems that it&amp;rsquo;s worth in the short term.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>