<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Hello_world</title>
        <link>https://jamied.me/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Hello_world</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 20:15:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://jamied.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Saving Lockdown</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/saving-lockdown/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 20:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/saving-lockdown/</guid>
            <description>Emergency surgery on the Xbox Kinect Phew! Tonight I saved lockdown in our household by fixing the Xbox Kinect :) Not many people seam to care or use the Kinect anymore, it was ahead of it&amp;rsquo;s time and never really got the traction it deserved. However, Just Dance 2021 (and previous versions) still supports it on the Xbox One.
Just Dance screen time is one I don&amp;rsquo;t mind the kids having, I&amp;rsquo;m an ex-breaker, so always happy to encourage dancing and listening to music.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="emergency-surgery-on-the-xbox-kinect">Emergency surgery on the Xbox Kinect</h2>

<p>Phew! Tonight I saved lockdown in our household by fixing the Xbox Kinect :)  Not many people seam to care or use the Kinect anymore, it was ahead of it&rsquo;s time and never really got the traction it deserved.  However, <a href="https://www.ubisoft.com/en-gb/game/just-dance/2021" target="_blank">Just Dance 2021</a> (and previous versions) still supports it on the Xbox One.</p>

<p>Just Dance screen time is one I don&rsquo;t mind the kids having, I&rsquo;m an ex-breaker, so always happy to encourage dancing and listening to music.  In previous UK lockdown(s), given the choice of watching Joe Wicks on YouTube every morning vs a family dance-off, Just Dance was always the firm favourite for our daily exercise.</p>

<h2 id="it-s-dead-daddy">&ldquo;It&rsquo;s dead Daddy&rdquo;</h2>

<p>So when I was told that the Kinect was dead, I was gutted, not for me, but for the family. It was time to get the screwdriver and perform whatever surgery I could to revive this little box of tricks.</p>

<h2 id="probably-just-a-fuse">&ldquo;Probably just a fuse&rdquo;</h2>

<p>Optimistically I declared &ldquo;it&rsquo;s probably just a fuse&rdquo;, which actually was true.  Problem is, replacing it is a PITA.</p>

<h2 id="step-by-step">Step by Step</h2>

<p>If your Xbox Kinect is completely dead ie. displays no lights, nada - then chances are it&rsquo;s the internal fuse.  If it still works, but has other issues, this guide is NOT for you.</p>

<p>You&rsquo;ll need a replacement 102 degree, 3 Amp fuse like this <a href="https://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/121428294599" target="_blank">one</a>.</p>

<p>First off, remove the stickers that cover the torx screws.  I used some tweezers to gently pry this off.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect1.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>There are 4 torx screws on both sides of the stand, the top row are security torx screws which are fiddly to remove.  I managed to remove 2 of them using a normal torx screwdriver, the other two I used a small flat-head between the center pin and one of the star edges to gently rotate the screw. Luckily they weren&rsquo;t that tight so this wasn&rsquo;t too tricky.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect2.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Now you can lift off the bottom casing to reveal 9 gold torx screws.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect3.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Both side panels will pop out.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect4.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>There are two black torx screws on either side, once removed the top case can be removed.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect5.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Now remove the 9 gold torx screws from the circuit board</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect6.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>This should release the remaining part of the unit.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect7.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>The fuse can be removed by putting some tweezers around the fuse connector (see arrow) and applying a small amount of horizontal force (from left to right).</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect8.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect9.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Remove the fuse from the connector, then twist the crimp connectors off of the fuse.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect10.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Trim the new fuse.  Here I&rsquo;ve soldered the crimp connectors back on - if doing so, be careful not to overheat the fuse.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect11.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Then fit the crimp connectors back into the connector housing.</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect11.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect12.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Before re-assembling plug in and check all working (obvs being careful of the exposed electronics)</p>

<p><img src="/img/Kinect13.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>Now unplug, piece back together and get you dancing shoes on 💃</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Ikea Tradfri switch hack</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/ikea-tradfri-switch-hack/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 18:20:51 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/ikea-tradfri-switch-hack/</guid>
            <description>Here I&amp;rsquo;m modifying an Ikea Tradfri Wireless Dimmer switch, one of the cheapest Zigbee buttons on the market at £6, into an industrial mechanical switch.
I wanted a rugged button to control some smart home devices, the Fibaro The Button, whilst looks great, IMHO it&amp;rsquo;s over priced at nearly £50. This post looks to create a much cheaper alternative and have some fun with a soldering iron along the way.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p><img src="/img/ikea button box.jpg" width="400"/></p>

<p>Here I&rsquo;m modifying an <a href="https://www.ikea.com/gb/en/p/tradfri-wireless-dimmer-white-00468432/" target="_blank">Ikea Tradfri Wireless Dimmer</a> switch, one of the cheapest Zigbee buttons on the market at £6, into an industrial mechanical switch.</p>

<p><img src="/img/ikea button modification.jpg" width="400"/></p>

<p>I wanted a rugged button to control some smart home devices, the Fibaro <a href="https://www.fibaro.com/en/products/the-button/" target="_blank">The Button</a>, whilst looks great, IMHO it&rsquo;s over priced at nearly £50.  This post looks to create a much cheaper alternative and have some fun with a soldering iron along the way.</p>

<p>The Ikea button is tiny at 45mm x 45mm, 16mm deep and runs off a single CR2032 coin battery.  It has 2 micro switch based buttons that can detect either being <code>pressed</code> or <code>held</code> within the SmartThings environment.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take this this button apart and see what&rsquo;s inside.  Before doing any modifications (at your own risk), I recommend you first pair this device with your existing home automation environment so that you can test the buttons are working correctly.</p>

<h2 id="ikea-tradfri-wireless-dimmer-teardown">Ikea Tradfri Wireless Dimmer Teardown</h2>

<p><img src="/img/ikea button teardown.jpg" width="400"></p>

<h2 id="circuit-board">Circuit board</h2>

<p><img src="/img/ikea button board.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>We can add a mechanical switch inline across either the purple or red terminals shown below on either of the onboard micro switches S1 or S2.</p>

<p><img src="/img/ikea button board annotated.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>I decided to completely remove the micro switches and hoped to use their existing copper pads, but in removing them, the copper seating got damaged so I needed to put the new inline switch for S1 across one existing switch pad and R7 and the S2 switch from one remaining pad to R6.  Then used some hot glue to secure the new wires connections in place.</p>

<p><img src="/img/ikea button board glue.jpg" width="400"></p>

<h2 id="industrial-button">Industrial button</h2>

<p>I used this industrial style switch, which I got from Ebay for £7, which had just enough space for the Ikea smart button circuit board and battery casing.  It was then a simple case of putting the wires for both the S1 and S2 switches in either side of the new mechanical switch terminals.  Note on this particular switch, one button is Normally Open (NO) and the other is Normally Closed (NC).  So the NO button detects both being <code>pressed</code> or <code>held</code>, and the NC button detects being <code>held</code> within the standard SmartThings Ikea Button device handler.</p>

<p><img src="/img/ikea mechanical internal.jpg" width="400"></p>

<h2 id="new-mechanical-button">New mechanical button</h2>

<p>The final result, a light weight industrial switch.
<img src="/img/ikea mechanical button.jpg" width="400"></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Google Nest SmartThings Integration</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/google-nest-smartthings-integration/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 11:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/01/google-nest-smartthings-integration/</guid>
            <description>Google Nest is now officially supported on SmartThings, until now I&amp;rsquo;d been using the awesome Nest Manager by Tonesto7 - but decided to take the plunge and see what this new integration looks like.
This blog takes you through the process of migrating your Nest account over to Google Nest, then integrating any Nest devices you have into your SmartThings environment. The process is easy, but long winded, it&amp;rsquo;s also irreversible, so this will show you what to expect during the SmartThings migration.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Google Nest is now officially supported on SmartThings, until now I&rsquo;d been using the awesome <a href="https://github.com/tonesto7/nest-manager" target="_blank">Nest Manager by Tonesto7</a> - but decided to take the plunge and see what this new integration looks like.</p>

<p>This blog takes you through the process of migrating your Nest account over to Google Nest, then integrating any Nest devices you have into your SmartThings environment.  The process is easy, but long winded, it&rsquo;s also <strong>irreversible</strong>, so this will show you what to expect during the SmartThings migration.</p>

<p>From the SmartThings application:</p>

<ol>
<li>Select &ldquo;Add device&rdquo; and then Google Nest: <img src="/img/nest01.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Select your Nest device from the options Cameras/Doorbells/Thermostats (here I&rsquo;ve selected Thermostats): <img src="/img/nest02.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Start the Nest account migration process: <img src="/img/nest03.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Enable Third Party cookies within your browser: <img src="/img/nest04.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest05.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest06.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest07.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest08.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest09.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Allow Nest access to your Google account: <img src="/img/nest10.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Sign into Nest: <img src="/img/nest11.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Disconnect existing &ldquo;Works with Nest&rdquo; connections: <img src="/img/nest12.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest13.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest14.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Agree to the Google T&amp;Cs: <img src="/img/nest15.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest16.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest17.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest18.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest19.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Select your email alerts: <img src="/img/nest20.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest21.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest22.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Allow SmartThings to control Google Nest: <img src="/img/nest23.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest24.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest25.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest26.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest27.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest28.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>Complete setup: <img src="/img/nest29.jpg" width="250"><br><img src="/img/nest30.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>View your new Nest device: <img src="/img/nest31.jpg" width="250"></li>
<li>View Nest automation options: <img src="/img/nest32.jpg" width="250"></li>
</ol>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Smart Home Multiplayer Bomb Disposal Game / Escape Room</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 20:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</guid>
            <description>About 18 months ago I shared some insight into some home automation I&amp;rsquo;d added that turned the whole house into a gaming zone. This has been pretty useful during the recent covid lockdown and provided much entertainment for the family. This post is to explain how it works.
Game objective Find and defuse the bomb without getting spotted. A baddie has hidden a bomb somewhere around the house, the bomb disposal team have been sent in to locate and defuse it - without activating any of the movement or contact sensors around the house.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p><img src="/img/tnt.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>About 18 months ago I shared some insight into some <a href="https://jamied.me/posts/2019/05/home-automation/" target="_blank">home automation</a> I&rsquo;d added that turned the whole house into a gaming zone.  This has been pretty useful during the recent covid lockdown and provided much entertainment for the family.  This post is to explain how it works.</p>

<h2 id="game-objective">Game objective</h2>

<p>Find and defuse the bomb without getting spotted.  A baddie has hidden a bomb somewhere around the house, the bomb disposal team have been sent in to locate and defuse it - without activating any of the movement or contact sensors around the house.</p>

<p>Each room has a sensor - so you need to be a ninja to get in and out of a room without activating any.  Check each room until you find the bomb, use the special disarm key to disable the bomb and end the game.  If you trigger a sensor, you will be alerted by an alarm and flashing lights - you&rsquo;ve failed your objective.</p>

<h2 id="how-it-works">How it works</h2>

<h3 id="motion-sensors">Motion sensors</h3>

<p>The game is designed on the SmartThings platform, using multiple motion sensors that are registered as devices for each room. Our house had an existing hard-wired alarm installation, adding a Konnected Alarm Interface Panel, exposes each PIR onto the SmartThings platform as a motion sensor device.</p>

<p><img src="/img/konnected.png"></p>

<p>Existing hard-wired PIRs become a SmartThings motion sensor.  Allowing you to create automations based off any detected movement.
<img src="/img/sensors.png"></p>

<h3 id="smartthings-groovy-app">SmartThings Groovy app</h3>

<p>I then wrote a custom SmartThings app which detects any motion or contact sensor changes.  If movement is detected or a contact sensor state changes, the app will simultaneously flash multiple Philips Hue bulbs around the home to a pre-set colour.  In addition, it invokes an Azure Function to playback a given audio track (full source available <a href="https://github.com/daltskin/ST-HomeAutomation" target="_blank">here</a>).  The app is fully customisable so you can easily change the in-game settings - such as which sensors to use, audio track, volume, light colours etc.</p>

<p><img src="/img/groovy.jpg" width="400"></p>

<h3 id="playing-music">Playing music</h3>

<p>An important part of the game ambience and to provide feedback is playing music whenever a motion sensor has been triggered.  This is controlled using an Azure Function to call the  Spotify API (full source available <a href="https://github.com/daltskin/ST-HomeAutomation" target="_blank">here</a>) to play a given track from a selected playlist.  The function allows you to seek to a specific position in a track, and to set playback duration.  Allowing you to playback a sample from any given song.  Currently I&rsquo;m using Run by AWOLNATION, recently popular on TikTok.  Another nice feature is the ability to select which Spotify connected audio device to use, allowing me to use the otherwise defunct Harmon Kardon Invoke 😀.</p>

<h3 id="arming-disarming-the-bomb">Arming/Disarming the bomb</h3>

<p>The SmartThings platform allows you to create different &ldquo;modes&rdquo; for your house automation such as Home/Away/Night etc.  Most normal people add additional modes for Movies etc, I geeked out on this and created a <code>Game</code> mode.  Which allows my groovy app to only trigger if the relevant mode is active.  I&rsquo;ve also created a SmartThings scene called <code>Game mode</code>, so to start the game, I can simply ask Alexa - &ldquo;Turn on Game mode&rdquo;.  Which will immediately activate all of the motion sensors around the house ready for action.</p>

<p>Creating the &ldquo;bomb&rdquo; out of an old cardboard box, a repurposed light gun and a SmartThings multi-purpose sensor.</p>

<p><img src="/img/parts.png"></p>

<p>The multi-purpose sensor allows the contact sensor&rsquo;s magnetic piece to be removed, and thus becomes the &ldquo;denotation disarm key&rdquo;.  The rest of the sensor is embedded in the bomb.</p>

<p><img src="/img/bomb.png"></p>

<p>When the magnet is added, it disarms the bomb (closes the connection) by changing the game mode back to the default (home) - using this simple SmartThings Automation:</p>

<p><img src="/img/disarm.jpg" width="400"></p>

<p>To start over, hide the bomb, then put the house back into <code>Game</code> mode.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Troubleshooting ARM DeploymentScripts</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/troubleshooting-arm-deploymentscripts/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 15:41:28 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/troubleshooting-arm-deploymentscripts/</guid>
            <description>The new ARM resource type Microsoft.Resources/deploymentScripts allows you to execute scripts within template deployments, capture the script outputs and re-use them later within the rest of the template.
Whilst the documentation goes some way to help you monitor and troubleshoot when the script doesn&amp;rsquo;t work as planned using the provided script service storage accounts, out of the box,I didn&amp;rsquo;t find these particularly helpful to identify why I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting the required outputs from my inline bash script.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>The new ARM resource type <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/deployment-script-template" target="_blank"><code>Microsoft.Resources/deploymentScripts</code></a> allows you to execute scripts within template deployments, capture the script outputs and re-use them later within the rest of the template.</p>

<p>Whilst the documentation goes some way to help you <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/deployment-script-template#monitor-and-troubleshoot-deployment-scripts" target="_blank">monitor and troubleshoot</a> when the script doesn&rsquo;t work as planned using the provided script service storage accounts, out of the box,I didn&rsquo;t find these particularly helpful to identify why I wasn&rsquo;t getting the required outputs from my inline bash script.</p>

<p>In order to help yourself debug, you&rsquo;ll need to change the <code>cleanUpPreference</code> property, the default <code>onSuccess</code> will clear down the debug contents, meaning you don&rsquo;t have anywhere to grab the output logs from.  Careful here, as <code>onSuccess</code> could just mean that your script executed ok, not necessarily that it provided the result you expected.  Here I&rsquo;m setting it to <code>onExpiration</code> to the provided <code>retentionInterval</code> period.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-json" data-lang="json"><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;properties&#34;</span><span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">:</span> 
{
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;forceUpdateTag&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;[parameters(&#39;utcValue&#39;)]&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;AzCliVersion&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;2.15.0&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;timeout&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;PT30M&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;arguments&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;scriptContent&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;cleanupPreference&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;OnExpiration&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;retentionInterval&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;P1D&#34;</span>
}</code></pre></div>
<h2 id="using-inline-scripts">Using inline scripts</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;m not usually a fan of condensing multiple lines of any script (bash/powershell) into one line, which you&rsquo;ll then need to escape, so that you can smash it into a json property within the ARM template - making it totally unreadable for your future self (or unfortunate others).  However, sometimes it makes the dev-loop quicker when you&rsquo;re still working things out with the rest of your automated deployment.</p>

<p>So, when your scriptContent doesn&rsquo;t work as planned, you&rsquo;ve triple-checked it works locally, what are you now supposed to do?  It&rsquo;s a black-hole debug experience, or so I initially thought&hellip;</p>

<h2 id="deploymentscript-artifacts">DeploymentScript artifacts</h2>

<p>As mentioned earlier, all of the script files are stored within the provided script storage account.</p>

<ul>
<li><code>azscriptinput</code>

<ul>
<li><code>DeploymentScript.sh</code> - Azure Cli deployment script execution engine uses this script to initialize context and collect outputs of user script execution</li>
<li><code>userscript.sh</code> - The contents of the scriptContent property (not very useful)</li>
</ul></li>
<li><code>azscriptoutput</code>

<ul>
<li><code>executionresult.json</code> - Execution summary of script start/end time and the overall result (half-useful)</li>
<li><code>scriptoutputs.json</code> - The json output of your bash script (only useful if the script works as intended)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="deploymentscript-json-outputs">DeploymentScript json outputs</h2>

<p>As per the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/templates/deployment-script-template?tabs=CLI#work-with-outputs-from-cli-script" target="_blank">documentation</a> your bash script MUST output json conforming to the following schema:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-json" data-lang="json">{
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;result&#34;</span>: {
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;property1&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;value&#34;</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;property2&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;value&#34;</span>
  }
}</code></pre></div>
<p>And within your ARM template outputs you need to reference this output values like this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-json" data-lang="json"><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;outputs&#34;</span><span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">:</span> {
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;Property1OutputVar&#34;</span>: {
        <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;value&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;[reference(&#39;runBashWithOutputs&#39;).outputs.result.property1]&#34;</span>,
        <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;type&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;string&#34;</span>
    },
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;Property2OutputVar&#34;</span>: {
        <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;value&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;[reference(&#39;runBashWithOutputs&#39;).outputs.result.property2]&#34;</span>,
        <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;type&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;string&#34;</span>
    }        
}</code></pre></div>
<p>In my case, my inline script was executing successfully, but my actual values were empty:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-json" data-lang="json">{
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;result&#34;</span>: {
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;appId&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;&#34;</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;appSecret&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;&#34;</span>
  }
}</code></pre></div>
<h2 id="az-scripts-path-output-directory">AZ_SCRIPTS_PATH_OUTPUT_DIRECTORY</h2>

<p>Time to add some debugging into our script, but how can we do that?  Looking in the <code>DeploymentScript.sh</code> mentioned above, you&rsquo;ll find a bunch of other variables, one of which is <code>AZ_SCRIPTS_PATH_OUTPUT_DIRECTORY</code>, so we can use this location to dump any of our custom script outputs to 😀</p>

<p>So by doing the following in the inline script, we can now add some tracing inside the script, and the output will be moved into the storage account with the rest of the outputs.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-json" data-lang="json"><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;properties&#34;</span><span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">:</span> 
{
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;AzCliVersion&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;2.15.0&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;forceUpdateTag&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;[parameters(&#39;utcValue&#39;)]&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;timeout&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;PT30M&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;arguments&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;[parameters(&#39;appName&#39;)]&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;scriptContent&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;appName=$1; echo $appName &gt; $AZ_SCRIPTS_PATH_OUTPUT_DIRECTORY/app; echo $(az account list) &gt; $AZ_SCRIPTS_PATH_OUTPUT_DIRECTORY/account; ...&lt;rest of script has been removed&gt;&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;cleanupPreference&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;OnExpiration&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;retentionInterval&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;P1D&#34;</span>
}</code></pre></div>
<p>Here you can see I&rsquo;m dumping both the input appName parameter value and the output from the <code>az account list</code> command to different files in the script storage output:</p>

<p><img src="/img/deploymentscript.png" width="800"></p>

<p>Hope this helps others.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>GitHub Webhooks With C# Azure Functions and SmartThings</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions-and-smartthings/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 19:54:39 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions-and-smartthings/</guid>
            <description>Ever since I saw Martin WoodWard&amp;rsquo;s Brian the Build Bunny for Team Foundation Server over 12 years ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated by creating signals for continuous integration builds. Following on from my last post, where I walk through creating and setting up a GitHub Webhook with Azure Functions, the next logical step was to integrate this to SmartThings for complete home automation.
SmartThings has a new REST API, which I&amp;rsquo;ve created and released a SmartThings NET library, which gives you the ability to interrogate your SmartThings home automation ecosystem entirely using dotnet.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p><img src="/img/buildbot-s.jpg" width="250"></p>

<p>Ever since I saw <a href="https://github.com/martinwoodward" target="_blank">Martin WoodWard&rsquo;s</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=5&amp;v=Is32fWJJA-I&amp;feature=emb_logo" target="_blank">Brian the Build Bunny</a> for Team Foundation Server over 12 years ago, I&rsquo;ve been fascinated by creating signals for continuous integration builds.  Following on from my <a href="/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions">last post</a>, where I walk through creating and setting up a GitHub Webhook with Azure Functions, the next logical step was to integrate this to SmartThings for complete home automation.</p>

<p>SmartThings has a new REST API, which I&rsquo;ve created and released a <a href="https://github.com/daltskin/SmartThingsNet" target="_blank">SmartThings NET library</a>, which gives you the ability to interrogate your SmartThings home automation ecosystem entirely using dotnet.  This makes it very easy to invoke SmartThings devices from a C# Azure Function, simply by adding the <a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/SmartThingsNet/" target="_blank">SmartThings NET NuGet package</a>.</p>

<p>Having an Azure Function run as a GitHub webhook gives you limitless home automation capability for your build statuses.  For example you could set off the house alarm, turn off the TV or open the blinds when the builds breaks.  Then dim the lights and play chilled music when the build succeeds.</p>

<h2 id="architecture">Architecture</h2>

<p><img src="/img/github_smartthings.png"></p>

<p>It all starts with a commit to a repo, which triggers the workflow.  This will start the build process, then on completion, invoke the webhook with an HTTP POST of the check suites status.  The SmartThings Azure Function checks the build success/failure and then executes the corresponding SmartThings scene using the SmartThings NET library.</p>

<h2 id="setup">Setup</h2>

<p>To set this up, first read <a href="/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions">GitHub Webhooks with C# Azure Functions</a>, then follow the additional steps in the repo here: <a href="https://github.com/daltskin/GitHubWebhookSmartThings" target="_blank">https://github.com/daltskin/GitHubWebhookSmartThings</a></p>

<h2 id="github-ci-end-to-end-demo">GitHub CI - End to End Demo</h2>

<p>In the following video, I&rsquo;m using a Philips Hue light bulb, connected through SmartThings.  The GitHub repo has been configured with a workflow and has a GitHub webhook for <code>Check suites</code> enabled - calling the published Azure Function endpoint.  So any commit will trigger the workflow, which in turn will invoke the webhook (Azure Function) and then execute the relevant SmartThings scene.</p>

<p><video src="/video/GitHubSmartThings.mp4" controls width=800></p>

<p>Here, I make a breaking change directly to the GitHub repo via the portal, by removing the <code>using</code> statement within a class file and committing the change. This runs the CI build, which then fails (as expected).  I then flip quickly to the Azure Portal, watching the live log of the published Azure Function endpoint.  The function gets invoked by GitHub with the check suites payload.  The function then executes the broken build scene within SmartThings, turning the robot light red.  I then go back to the GitHub portal, edit the class file, re-introducing the <code>using</code> statement and commit the change.  This time the Azure Function now runs the success build scene - turning the Robot light green.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>GitHub Webhooks With C# Azure Functions</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 21:50:17 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/github-webhooks-with-azure-functions/</guid>
            <description>Recently I wanted to build a GitHub webhook using C# Azure Functions, but could only find an example template using Node.js. Here, I set out to create a webhook to check the overall status of a build. This is something I was doing around 10 years ago with Team Foundation Server, so thought it would be fun to get this up and running with GitHub Actions.
Check Suites Looking at the available webhook events there wasn&amp;rsquo;t an obvious event I could subscribe to get what I wanted.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Recently I wanted to build a GitHub webhook using C# Azure Functions, but could only find an example template using <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/monitor-github-events-with-a-function-triggered-by-a-webhook/" target="_blank">Node.js</a>.  Here, I set out to create a webhook to check the overall status of a build.  This is something I was doing around 10 years ago with Team Foundation Server, so thought it would be fun to get this up and running with <a href="https://github.com/features/actions" target="_blank">GitHub Actions</a>.</p>

<h2 id="check-suites">Check Suites</h2>

<p>Looking at the <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/developers/webhooks-and-events/webhook-events-and-payloads" target="_blank">available webhook events</a> there wasn&rsquo;t an obvious event I could subscribe to get what I wanted.  Currently, there isn&rsquo;t an OTB event for when workflows complete.  This has been asked a couple of times on the <a href="https://github.community/t/github-webhooks-to-notify-when-workflows-are-completed/118941" target="_blank">GitHub community</a> - so I hope will be addressed soon.  In addition, there are some marketplace solutions for Webhook Actions: <a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/webhook-action" target="_blank">Webhook Action</a> and <a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/workflow-webhook-action" target="_blank">Workflow Webhook Action</a> which you can use anywhere within your workflows to trigger a webhook.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, I settled on the <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/developers/webhooks-and-events/webhook-events-and-payloads#check_suite" target="_blank">check suite</a> event subscription since it returns the summary <code>conclusion</code> for all the check runs that are part of a check suite.  By default, GitHub creates a check suite automatically when code is pushed to the repository.</p>

<p><img src="/img/webhook check suites event.png"></p>

<h2 id="c-azure-function-webhook">C# Azure Function webhook</h2>

<p>To create the endpoint that GitHub calls, I wanted to use a lightweight serverless approach.  Using Visual Studio you can use the C# Azure Function HTTP Trigger template to get up and running quickly.  The below code extract shows how the received json payload can be deserialized and interrogated.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">public</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">static</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">class</span> <span style="color:#a6e22e">GitHubWebhook</span>
{
<span style="color:#a6e22e">    [FunctionName(&#34;GitHubWebhook&#34;)]</span>
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">public</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">static</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">async</span> Task&lt;IActionResult&gt; Run(
<span style="color:#a6e22e">        [HttpTrigger(AuthorizationLevel.Function, &#34;post&#34;, Route = null)]</span> HttpRequest req, 
        ILogger log)
    {
        log.LogInformation(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;C# Webhook for GitHub.&#34;</span>);
        <span style="color:#66d9ef">string</span> requestBody = <span style="color:#66d9ef">await</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> StreamReader(req.Body).ReadToEndAsync();
        CheckSuiteStatus suiteStatus = JsonConvert.DeserializeObject&lt;CheckSuiteStatus&gt;(requestBody);
        <span style="color:#66d9ef">string</span> responseMessage = <span style="color:#e6db74">$&#34;The GitHub Check Suite status for {suiteStatus.check_suite.id} {suiteStatus.action} with {suiteStatus.check_suite.conclusion}&#34;</span>;
        <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> OkObjectResult(responseMessage);            
    }
}
</code></pre></div>
<p>An extract of the <code>application/json</code> payload GitHub sends for the <code>check suites</code> event can be seen below:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-json" data-lang="json">{
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;action&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;completed&#34;</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;check_suite&#34;</span>: {
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;id&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">941142538</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;head_branch&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;master&#34;</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;status&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;completed&#34;</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;conclusion&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;success&#34;</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;app&#34;</span>: {
      <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;id&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#ae81ff">15368</span>,
      <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;slug&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;github-actions&#34;</span>,
      <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;name&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;GitHub Actions&#34;</span>,
      <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;description&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Automate your workflow from idea to production&#34;</span>,
      <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;external_url&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;https://help.github.com/en/actions&#34;</span>,
      <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;html_url&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;https://github.com/apps/github-actions&#34;</span>,
    }
  }
}</code></pre></div>
<p>For an example of the full payload go here: <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/developers/webhooks-and-events/webhook-events-and-payloads#webhook-payload-example-1" target="_blank">webhook payload example</a>.</p>

<h2 id="debugging-with-tunnel-relay">Debugging with Tunnel Relay</h2>

<p>Whilst debugging, GitHub needs a public addressable endpoint to invoke.  Obviously this is a problem if you&rsquo;re hosting on localhost, so you can use a tool like <a href="https://ngrok.com/" target="_blank">ngrok</a>.  However, I&rsquo;ve chosen to use the relatively new (and free) <a href="https://github.com/OfficeDev/microsoft-teams-tunnelrelay" target="_blank">Tunnel Relay</a> tool which creates a secure tunnel using Azure Relay with a static address 😀</p>

<p><img src="/img/webhook tunnel relay.png"></p>

<p>In the screenshot above you can see the Azure Function 200 result that has been sent back to GitHub.  We don&rsquo;t expect GitHub to actually do anything with this response - but we can use it to check our Azure Function is working ok.</p>

<p><img src="/img/webhook running.png"></p>

<h2 id="workflow-manual-triggers">Workflow Manual Triggers</h2>

<p>To make the development cycle quicker, I used a manual trigger using the new <a href="https://github.blog/changelog/2020-07-06-github-actions-manual-triggers-with-workflow_dispatch/" target="_blank">workflow_dispatch</a>.  Adding the following lines to an existing workflow, means that you can manually invoke it:</p>

<p>so my workflow yaml now looks like this:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-yaml" data-lang="yaml">name: .NET Core

on:
  workflow_dispatch:
    inputs:
      logLevel:
        description: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;Log level&#39;</span>     
        required: <span style="color:#66d9ef">true</span>
        default: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#39;warning&#39;</span></code></pre></div>
<p>So you can now trigger it from the Actions tab without having to perform any commits:</p>

<p><img src="/img/workflow dispatch.png"></p>

<h2 id="securing-the-webhook">Securing the Webhook</h2>

<p>We want to ensure our trigger can only get called by GitHub and not some other spurious source.  So we set a secret in the Webhooks Manage page:</p>

<p><img src="/img/webhook secret.png"></p>

<p>GitHub will use this secret to create a hash signature of the entire payload and pass the signature within the <code>X-Hub-Signature</code> request header.  Within our C# Azure Function we also need to store the same environment setting as <code>Secret</code> so we can compute a hash on the payload and check that it matches the one we&rsquo;ve been sent from GitHub.  If running locally, you can set this in the the local.settings.json file eg:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-json" data-lang="json">{
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;IsEncrypted&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#66d9ef">false</span>,
  <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;Values&#34;</span>: {
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;AzureWebJobsStorage&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;UseDevelopmentStorage=true&#34;</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;FUNCTIONS_WORKER_RUNTIME&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;dotnet&#34;</span>,
    <span style="color:#f92672">&#34;Secret&#34;</span>: <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;&#34;</span>
  }
}</code></pre></div>
<p>For more details on how GitHub recommends you secure webhooks see <a href="https://docs.github.com/en/developers/webhooks-and-events/securing-your-webhooks#validating-payloads-from-github" target="_blank">Securing your webhooks</a>.  To implement this, I&rsquo;ve used a simple Validate function:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">public</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">static</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">bool</span> Validate (<span style="color:#66d9ef">string</span> signature, <span style="color:#66d9ef">string</span> body, <span style="color:#66d9ef">string</span> secret)
{
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">string</span> expectedSignature = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;sha1=&#34;</span> + HMACSHA256(secret, body);
    <span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> expectedSignature.Equals(signature);
}
</code></pre></div>
<h2 id="publish-to-azure-functions">Publish to Azure Functions</h2>

<p>Here I&rsquo;ve used the <code>[HttpTrigger(AuthorizationLevel.Function)]</code>, so we need to grab the <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/functions-bindings-http-webhook-trigger?tabs=csharp#authorization-keys" target="_blank">Function access key</a> from the Azure portal:</p>

<p><img src="/img/function key.png"></p>

<p>This now forms part of the <code>?code=</code> querystring of the webhook Payload URL in the GitHub Webhook Manage page - which we now need to update from our development Tunnel Relay address.  The URL should look something like this: https://{yourfunc}.azurewebsites.net/api/GitHubWebhook?code=abcdefg123456==</p>

<h2 id="testing">Testing</h2>

<p>Finally, to ensure everything is hooked up and all the configuration is correct - let&rsquo;s manually trigger a workflow using workflow_dispatch and monitor the Azure Function at the same time.</p>

<p><video src="/video/GitHubAFWebhook.mp4" controls width=800></p>

<p>Full code here: <a href="https://github.com/daltskin/GitHubWebhookPlayground" target="_blank">GitHub Webhook Playground</a>.  This particular webhook doesn&rsquo;t actually do anything useful, other than interrogate the check suite conclusion and return a message back in the response payload to GitHub.  I plan to use this same mechanism to integrate GitHub into SmartThings, which I&rsquo;ll cover in a later post.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>LUIS DevOps with Github Actions</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/05/luis-devops-with-github-actions/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 16:58:32 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/05/luis-devops-with-github-actions/</guid>
            <description>Implementing good DevOps practices with the LUIS Cognitive Service has been traditionally hard. Largely because the initial focus of the service has been on the underlying performance and on the portal experience - making a complex machine learning problem easy to use by any developer. In fact, now the portal is so easy to use, it can be used by non-developers too, such as business folk and even content editors.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Implementing good DevOps practices with the LUIS Cognitive Service has been traditionally hard.  Largely because the initial focus of the service has been on the underlying performance and on the portal experience - making a complex machine learning problem easy to use by any developer.  In fact, now the portal is so easy to use, it can be used by non-developers too, such as business folk and even content editors.  The downside to this initial engineering focus, was that there was limited public API capability that you could leverage in order to automate some of the more ardous tasks typcially faced by enterprise organisations such as:</p>

<ul>
<li>Limited support for different environments</li>
<li>No/fragmented CLI tooling</li>
<li>Limited testing capability</li>
</ul>

<p><em>But, over the last 12+ months things have steady improved and much of these challenges have been addressed</em></p>

<h3 id="luis-multiple-api-endpoints-for-authoring-predictions">LUIS Multiple API Endpoints for authoring &amp; predictions:</h3>

<p>LUIS now offers a much richer public API, including separate endpoints:</p>

<ul>
<li>LUIS API Authoring: <a href="https://westus.dev.cognitive.microsoft.com/docs/services/luis-programmatic-apis-v3-0-preview" target="_blank">https://westus.dev.cognitive.microsoft.com/docs/services/luis-programmatic-apis-v3-0-preview</a></li>
<li>LUIS API Predictions: <a href="https://westus.dev.cognitive.microsoft.com/docs/services/luis-endpoint-api-v3-0" target="_blank">https://westus.dev.cognitive.microsoft.com/docs/services/luis-endpoint-api-v3-0</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="convergence-of-bot-framework-luis-cli-tooling">Convergence of Bot Framework/LUIS CLI Tooling</h3>

<p>What was once a fragmented toolset has now been converged into a single Bot Framework CLI tool:</p>

<ul>
<li>Bot Framework CLI: <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/bf-cli-overview?view=azure-bot-service-4.0" target="_blank">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/bf-cli-overview?view=azure-bot-service-4.0</a></li>
</ul>

<h3 id="devops-focus">DevOps Focus</h3>

<p>A set of DevOps tools for NLU services, including easy to use Azure DevOps Pipelines Tasks that do the heavy lifting for training/testing LUIS models:</p>

<ul>
<li>NLU.DevOps: <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/NLU.DevOps" target="_blank">https://github.com/microsoft/NLU.DevOps</a></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="luis-devops-with-github">LUIS DevOps with Github</h2>

<p>Now, there is guidance and best practice advice for settingup Github Actions: <a href="https://github.com/Azure-Samples/LUIS-DevOps-Template" target="_blank">https://github.com/Azure-Samples/LUIS-DevOps-Template</a>
which includes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Documentation</li>
<li>End-to-end walkthrough</li>
</ul>

<p>Covering:</p>

<ul>
<li>Github flow branch management</li>
<li>Setting up build agent dependencies</li>
<li>Handling secrets/environment variables</li>
<li>Azure authentication</li>
<li>Leveraging bf &amp; NLU.DevOps cli tools</li>
<li>Testing models</li>
<li>Analyzing model performance</li>
<li>Publishing models</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="continuous-integration-workflow-architecture">Continuous Integration Workflow architecture</h3>

<p>For the complete <a href="https://github.com/Azure-Samples/LUIS-DevOps-Template/blob/develop/.github/workflows/luis_ci.yaml" target="_blank">CI workflow</a> you can look in the repo, but it&rsquo;s useful to understand the key stages within the process:</p>

<p><img src="/img/luis_ci_workflow.png"></p>

<p>Note here, the initial publish of the model uses <code>curl post</code> rather than the <code>bf luis:application:publish</code> - at the time of writing this blog, there is is an issue with the bf cli tool when using the <code>--direct</code> publish switch.  However, this has now been addressed via this <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/botframework-cli/pull/798" target="_blank">PR</a> and will be in the next release of the tooling.</p>

<h3 id="pull-request-workflow-architecture">Pull Request Workflow architecture</h3>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/Azure-Samples/LUIS-DevOps-Template/blob/develop/.github/workflows/luis_pr.yaml" target="_blank">PR workflow</a> is much simpler:</p>

<p><img src="/img/luis_pr_workflow.png"></p>

<p>So, if you&rsquo;re interested in setting up Github Actions with LUIS - go check out the new resource: <a href="https://github.com/Azure-Samples/LUIS-DevOps-Template" target="_blank">https://github.com/Azure-Samples/LUIS-DevOps-Template</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Windows Terminal Command Line</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/02/windows-terminal-command-line/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 14:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/02/windows-terminal-command-line/</guid>
            <description>Following on from my previous post about WSL Shortcuts - Windows Terminal v0.9 Release finally introduces command line support.
You can now combine this with an old File Explorer task bar trick to bootstrap your awesomeness.
Windows Files Explorer &amp;amp; Windows Terminal All of command line parameters that are supported are documented here. One nice trick is using split-pane to support different platforms simultaneously. So the following will open up a pane with both Powershell and Ubuntu side-by-side :)</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Following on from my <a href="../../../2019/11/wsl-shortcuts/">previous post about WSL Shortcuts</a> - <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/terminal/releases/tag/v0.9.433.0" target="_blank">Windows Terminal v0.9 Release</a> finally introduces command line support.</p>

<p>You can now combine this with an old <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton/2017/08/03/windows-productivity-tip-file-explorer-command-prompt-and-back-from-the-current-directory/" target="_blank">File Explorer task bar trick</a> to bootstrap your awesomeness.</p>

<h2 id="windows-files-explorer-windows-terminal">Windows Files Explorer &amp; Windows Terminal</h2>

<p>All of command line parameters that are supported are documented <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/terminal/blob/master/doc/user-docs/UsingCommandlineArguments.md" target="_blank">here</a>. One nice trick is using <code>split-pane</code> to support different platforms simultaneously.  So the following will open up a pane with both Powershell and Ubuntu side-by-side :)</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">wt split-pane -p Ubuntu</code></pre></div>
<p>In the below video, my default command line is Powershell.  I&rsquo;m then executing both a Windows batch file and a Bash script simultaneously - both are downloading images to the same folder.</p>

<p><video src="/video/Windows Terminal.mp4" controls width=800></p>

<h2 id="windows-terminal-starting-folder">Windows Terminal Starting Folder</h2>

<p>As a side note, the default starting folder for each command line can be set in by the <code>startingDirectory</code> property for both environments in the profiles.json file eg:</p>

<pre><code>{
    &quot;acrylicOpacity&quot; : 0.75,
    &quot;closeOnExit&quot; : true,
    &quot;colorScheme&quot; : &quot;Campbell&quot;,
    &quot;commandline&quot; : &quot;cmd.exe&quot;,
    &quot;cursorColor&quot; : &quot;#FFFFFF&quot;,
    &quot;cursorShape&quot; : &quot;bar&quot;,
    &quot;fontFace&quot; : &quot;Consolas&quot;,
    &quot;fontSize&quot; : 10,
    &quot;guid&quot; : &quot;{0caa0dad-35be-5f56-a8ff-afceeeaa6101}&quot;,
    &quot;historySize&quot; : 9001,
    &quot;icon&quot; : &quot;ms-appx:///ProfileIcons/{0caa0dad-35be-5f56-a8ff-afceeeaa6101}.png&quot;,
    &quot;name&quot; : &quot;cmd&quot;,
    &quot;padding&quot; : &quot;0, 0, 0, 0&quot;,
    &quot;snapOnInput&quot; : true,
    &quot;startingDirectory&quot; : &quot;c://Github&quot;,
    &quot;useAcrylic&quot; : true
},
{
    &quot;acrylicOpacity&quot; : 0.5,
    &quot;closeOnExit&quot; : true,
    &quot;colorScheme&quot; : &quot;Campbell&quot;,
    &quot;commandline&quot; : &quot;wsl.exe -d Ubuntu&quot;,
    &quot;cursorColor&quot; : &quot;#FFFFFF&quot;,
    &quot;cursorShape&quot; : &quot;bar&quot;,
    &quot;fontFace&quot; : &quot;Consolas&quot;,
    &quot;fontSize&quot; : 10,
    &quot;guid&quot; : &quot;{2c4de342-38b7-51cf-b940-2309a097f518}&quot;,
    &quot;historySize&quot; : 9001,
    &quot;icon&quot; : &quot;ms-appx:///ProfileIcons/{9acb9455-ca41-5af7-950f-6bca1bc9722f}.png&quot;,
    &quot;name&quot; : &quot;Ubuntu&quot;,
    &quot;padding&quot; : &quot;0, 0, 0, 0&quot;,
    &quot;snapOnInput&quot; : true,
    &quot;useAcrylic&quot; : false,
    &quot;startingDirectory&quot; : &quot;c://Github&quot;,
},
</code></pre>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>WSL Shortcuts</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/wsl-shortcuts/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 09:24:13 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/wsl-shortcuts/</guid>
            <description>A while back I posted a couple of Windows productivity tips:
 File Explorer &amp;lt;&amp;gt; Command Prompt
 File Explorer &amp;gt; VS Code
  Windows Files Explorer &amp;amp; WSL.EXE Now that Windows SubSystem Linux is here, what if we want to drop straight from Windows File Explorer to, for example, the Ubuntu command line? So, assuming you have WSL already setup, type wsl straight into the Windows Explorer bar:</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>A while back I posted a couple of Windows productivity tips:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton/2017/08/03/windows-productivity-tip-file-explorer-command-prompt-and-back-from-the-current-directory/" target="_blank">File Explorer &lt;&gt; Command Prompt</a></p></li>

<li><p><a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton/2017/08/11/windows-productivity-tip-2-file-explorer-vs-code-at-the-current-directory/" target="_blank">File Explorer &gt; VS Code</a></p></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="windows-files-explorer-wsl-exe">Windows Files Explorer &amp; WSL.EXE</h2>

<p>Now that <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/about" target="_blank">Windows SubSystem Linux</a> is here, what if we want to drop straight from Windows File Explorer to, for example, the Ubuntu command line?  So, assuming you have WSL already setup, type <code>wsl</code> straight into the Windows Explorer bar:</p>

<p><video src="/video/WSL.mp4" controls width=800></p>

<p>Pretty awesome right?</p>

<p>So now you can do all sorts of useful things straight on your Windows filesystem, but from Linux.  Take for example this *.gz file I have, I don&rsquo;t have <a href="https://www.7-zip.org/" target="_blank">7-Zip</a> installed on my Windows machine, but now I don&rsquo;t need to bother installing it - as I can use the built-in gunzip support from Ubuntu:</p>

<p><video src="/video/gunzip.mp4" controls width=800></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>WebWindow</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/webwindow/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/webwindow/</guid>
            <description>This week Steve Sanderson blogged again, this time introducing his latest wizardry WebWindow - a lightweight cross-platform webview library for .NET Core.
He also shared the full source code and provided some great examples on what&amp;rsquo;s possible:
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last couple of evenings experimenting with this a bit. Whilst it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;super-pre-alpha quality&amp;rsquo;, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty damn awesome.
Docker Using this in conjunction with Docker.DotNet was my first experiment. Rather than bring web content into the project, why not let Docker do the local hosting.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>This week <a href="https://twitter.com/StevenSanderson" target="_blank">Steve Sanderson</a> blogged again, this time introducing his latest wizardry <a href="https://blog.stevensanderson.com/2019/11/18/2019-11-18-webwindow-a-cross-platform-webview-for-dotnet-core/" target="_blank">WebWindow</a> - a lightweight cross-platform webview library for .NET Core.</p>

<p>He also shared the full <a href="https://github.com/SteveSandersonMS/WebWindow" target="_blank">source code</a> and provided some great <a href="https://github.com/SteveSandersonMS/WebWindow/tree/master/samples" target="_blank">examples</a> on what&rsquo;s possible:</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve spent the last couple of evenings experimenting with this a bit.  Whilst it&rsquo;s &lsquo;super-pre-alpha quality&rsquo;, it&rsquo;s pretty damn awesome.</p>

<h2 id="docker">Docker</h2>

<p>Using this in conjunction with <a href="https://github.com/microsoft/docker.dotnet" target="_blank">Docker.DotNet</a> was my first experiment.  Rather than bring web content into the project, why not let Docker do the local hosting.  So assuming you&rsquo;ve got Docker already setup on your developer machine, this is something you can play with.</p>

<p>I tried this first with the <a href="https://hub.docker.com/r/pengbai/docker-supermario/" target="_blank">docker-supermario</a> container by <a href="https://github.com/PengBAI" target="_blank">Peng BAI</a>, of Infinite Mario in HTML5 Javascript - the results were very impressive.</p>

<p><video src="/video/SuperMario.mp4" controls width=800></p>

<h2 id="hosted-html">Hosted HTML</h2>

<p>This time I experimented with the cross-platform aspect to this.  Using a hosted website, in this case <a href="https://mrdoob.com/lab/javascript/effects/solitaire/" target="_blank">Solitaire</a> by <a href="https://twitter.com/mrdoob" target="_blank">Mr Doob</a>.</p>

<p>I compiled both a standalone runtime for Windows and Linux using:</p>

<h3 id="windows">Windows</h3>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell">dotnet publish -o publish -c Debug -r win10-x64 /p<span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">:</span>PublishSingleFile=true /p<span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">:</span>PublishTrimmed=true</code></pre></div>
<h3 id="linux">Linux</h3>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">dotnet publish -o publish -c Debug -r linux-x64 /p:PublishSingleFile<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>true /p:PublishTrimmed<span style="color:#f92672">=</span>true</code></pre></div>
<p>The runtime sizes were 27,450KB and 36,744KB respectively.</p>

<p>Then it was time to test them both.  Using <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/p/windows-terminal-preview/9n0dx20hk701" target="_blank">Windows Terminal</a> and WSL (Ubuntu) here&rsquo;s what happened:</p>

<p><video src="/video/Solitaire.mp4" controls width=800></p>

<p>So what next?  Well, anything that&rsquo;s web related can be now hosted in this simple component.  Experimenting further, I just built a new Microsoft Teams client ;)</p>

<p><img src="/img/WebWindow MS Teams.png"></p>

<p>So, if you&rsquo;re a dab hand a C++ and want to help Steve advance this project, reach out to him at his repo: <a href="https://github.com/SteveSandersonMS/WebWindow" target="_blank">https://github.com/SteveSandersonMS/WebWindow</a></p>

<p>My own fork containing the above samples is here: <a href="https://github.com/daltskin/WebWindow" target="_blank">https://github.com/daltskin/WebWindow</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Pulumi Azure Bot Service</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/pulumi-azure-bot-service/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 20:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/11/pulumi-azure-bot-service/</guid>
            <description>Pulumi IaaC =&amp;gt; IaaC# (Infrastructure as CSharp) - Deploying Azure bots with Pulumi I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that, until a week ago, I had never heard of Pulumi, but when they recently announced support for .NET - they got my attention. I&amp;rsquo;ve worked alot with JSON based Azure Resource Manager (ARM) templates in the past - but these quickly become complicated to author when you have many different Azure resources.
Whilst Terraform offers it&amp;rsquo;s own HashiCorp Configuration Language (HCL), that or working with YAML makes a bit of me want to die - the syntax seems we&amp;rsquo;ve gone back an era in computing.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p><img src="/img/pulumi.png"></p>

<h2 id="pulumi-iaac-iaac-infrastructure-as-csharp-deploying-azure-bots-with-pulumi">Pulumi IaaC =&gt; IaaC# (Infrastructure as CSharp) - Deploying Azure bots with Pulumi</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;ll admit that, until a week ago, I had never heard of <a href="pulimi.com" target="_blank">Pulumi</a>, but when they recently announced <a href="https://www.pulumi.com/blog/dotnet-preview/" target="_blank">support for .NET</a> - they got my attention.  I&rsquo;ve worked alot with JSON based <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-resource-manager/resource-group-authoring-templates" target="_blank">Azure Resource Manager</a> (ARM) templates in the past - but these quickly become complicated to author when you have many different Azure resources.</p>

<p>Whilst Terraform offers it&rsquo;s own <a href="https://github.com/hashicorp/hcl" target="_blank">HashiCorp Configuration Language</a> (HCL), that or working with YAML makes a bit of me want to die - the syntax seems we&rsquo;ve gone back an era in computing.  So, after Pulumi&rsquo;s C# announcement I wanted to take a further look and see what the noise was all about.  What better way to kick the tyres than to deploy a brand new Azure Bot Service instance directly into Azure.</p>

<p>You can read about the <a href="https://www.pulumi.com/docs/intro/concepts/" target="_blank">Pulumi architecture and high level concepts</a>, to understand some of the basics and terminology.  Under the covers Pulumi uses the Azure GO SDK which calls the Azure Management API.  Once you&rsquo;ve configured your IaaC, you can then integrate it into <a href="https://www.pulumi.com/docs/guides/continuous-delivery/azure-devops/" target="_blank">Azure DevOps Pipelines</a> or <a href="https://www.pulumi.com/docs/guides/continuous-delivery/github-actions/" target="_blank">GitHub Actions</a>.</p>

<h3 id="deploying-azure-bot-service-with-pulumi-c-sdk">Deploying Azure Bot Service with Pulumi C# SDK</h3>

<p>Essentially to deploy a Web App Bot within Azure Bot Services (ABS) requires several things:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Azure resource</th>
<th>Description</th>
<th>Optional</th>
</tr>
</thead>

<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Resource Group</td>
<td>Container for the Azure resources</td>
<td></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>AAD Application ID and secret</td>
<td>AAD App registration and Authentication for the bot</td>
<td></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>App Service Plan</td>
<td>Defined set of compute resources for web app</td>
<td></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>AppService</td>
<td>Web API of the bot application</td>
<td></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Bot Service</td>
<td>ABS bot registration</td>
<td></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Application Insights</td>
<td>Telemetry/logging for bot application</td>
<td>*</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>Cognitive Services</td>
<td>Universal key for LUIS/QnA Maker etc</td>
<td>*</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<h3 id="declaring-this-in-pulumi-csharp">Declaring this in Pulumi CSharp</h3>

<p>Let&rsquo;s take a look at the individual code segments that can be used to provision the above Azure services.  A link to a complete sample is provided at the bottom of this post:</p>

<h4 id="azure-resource-group">Azure Resource Group</h4>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> resourceGroup = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> ResourceGroup(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;botservice-rg&#34;</span>);
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-ad-application-registration">Azure AD Application Registration</h4>

<p>This requires the additional <a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Pulumi.AzureAD/" target="_blank">Pulumi.Azuread</a> provider nuget package (this took me a while to figure out).</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> msa = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Application(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;msapp&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> ApplicationArgs
{
    Oauth2AllowImplicitFlow = <span style="color:#66d9ef">false</span>,
    AvailableToOtherTenants = <span style="color:#66d9ef">true</span>,
    PublicClient = <span style="color:#66d9ef">true</span>
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-ad-application-secret">Azure AD Application Secret</h4>

<p>Here we can use the additional <a href="https://www.nuget.org/packages/Pulumi.Random" target="_blank">Pulumi.Random</a> provider nuget package to generate a strong password for the secret value and use that for the application password.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> pwd = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Random.RandomPassword(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;password&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Random.RandomPasswordArgs
{
    Length = <span style="color:#ae81ff">16</span>,
    MinNumeric = <span style="color:#ae81ff">1</span>,
    MinSpecial = <span style="color:#ae81ff">1</span>,
    MinUpper = <span style="color:#ae81ff">1</span>,
    MinLower = <span style="color:#ae81ff">1</span>
});

<span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> msaSecret = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> ApplicationPassword(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;msasecret&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> ApplicationPasswordArgs
{
    ApplicationObjectId = msa.ObjectId,
    EndDateRelative = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;8640h&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#75715e">// set whatever expiry you want
</span><span style="color:#75715e"></span>    Value = pwd.Result
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-app-service-plan">Azure App Service Plan</h4>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> appServicePlan = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Plan(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;asp&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> PlanArgs
{
    ResourceGroupName = resourceGroup.Name,
    Kind = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;App&#34;</span>,
    Sku = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> PlanSkuArgs
    {
        Tier = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Basic&#34;</span>,
        Size = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;B1&#34;</span>
    },
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-application-insights">Azure Application Insights</h4>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> appInsights = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> AppInsights.Insights(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;ai&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> AppInsights.InsightsArgs
{
    ApplicationType = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;web&#34;</span>,
    ResourceGroupName = resourceGroup.Name
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-application-insights-api-key">Azure Application Insights API Key</h4>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> appInsightApiKey = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> AppInsights.ApiKey(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;ai&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> AppInsights.ApiKeyArgs
{
    ApplicationInsightsId = appInsights.Id,
    ReadPermissions = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;api&#34;</span>,
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-cognitive-service-key">Azure Cognitive Service Key</h4>

<p>Universal key for any Azure Cognitive Services used by your bot.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> luis = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Cognitive.Account(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;cs&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Cognitive.AccountArgs
{
    Kind = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;CognitiveServices&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#75715e">// includes LUIS
</span><span style="color:#75715e"></span>    ResourceGroupName = resourceGroup.Name,
    Sku = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Cognitive.Inputs.AccountSkuArgs() { Name = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;S0&#34;</span>, Tier = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Standard&#34;</span> }
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-app-service">Azure App Service</h4>

<p>The web (API) application uses the Azure AD details and any Cognitive Service keys declared earlier.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> app = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> AppService(<span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;app&#34;</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> AppServiceArgs
{
    ResourceGroupName = resourceGroup.Name,
    AppServicePlanId = appServicePlan.Id,
    AppSettings =
    {
        { <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;WEBSITE_RUN_FROM_PACKAGE&#34;</span>, codeBlobUrl },
        { <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;MicrosoftAppId&#34;</span>, msa.ApplicationId },
        { <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;MicrosoftAppPassword&#34;</span>, msaSecret.Value },
        { <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;LuisApiKey&#34;</span>, luis.PrimaryAccessKey },
    },
    HttpsOnly = <span style="color:#66d9ef">true</span>
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="azure-bot-service">Azure Bot Service</h4>

<p>Then finally the Azure Bot Service pieces it all together.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">var</span> bot = <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Bot.WebApp(botName, <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Bot.WebAppArgs
{
    DisplayName = botName,
    MicrosoftAppId = msa.ApplicationId,
    ResourceGroupName = resourceGroup.Name,
    Sku = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;F0&#34;</span>,
    Location = <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;global&#34;</span>,
    Endpoint = Output.Format(<span style="color:#e6db74">$&#34;https://{app.DefaultSiteHostname}/api/messages&#34;</span>),
    DeveloperAppInsightsApiKey = appInsightApiKey.Key,
    DeveloperAppInsightsApplicationId = appInsights.AppId,
    DeveloperAppInsightsKey = appInsights.InstrumentationKey
});
</code></pre></div>
<h4 id="then-we-can-output-the-results">Then we can output the results</h4>

<p>Take the below outputs and put them straight into the Bot Framework Emulator and you&rsquo;ll be able to test the newly deployed bot.  Alternatively, use the Azure Portal Azure Bot Service - Test in Webchat feature.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-csharp" data-lang="csharp"><span style="color:#66d9ef">return</span> <span style="color:#66d9ef">new</span> Dictionary&lt;<span style="color:#66d9ef">string</span>, <span style="color:#66d9ef">object</span>&gt;
{
    { <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;Bot Endpoint&#34;</span>, bot.Endpoint },
    { <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;MicrosoftAppId&#34;</span>, msa.ApplicationId },
    { <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;MicrosoftAppPassword&#34;</span>, msaSecret.Value }
};
</code></pre></div>
<p><img src="/img/pulumibutton.svg"></p>

<h3 id="execute-the-pulumi-cli">Execute the Pulumi CLI</h3>
<div class="highlight"><pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">$ pulumi stack init dev
$ az login
$ pulumi config set azure:location <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;North Europe&#34;</span>
$ pulumi config set botName PulumiBot1
$ pulumi up</code></pre></div>
<h3 id="full-source-code-sample">Full source code sample</h3>

<p><del>At the time of writing I&rsquo;ve submitted a PR for a full sample here: <a href="https://github.com/pulumi/examples/pull/464" target="_blank">https://github.com/pulumi/examples/pull/464</a></del></p>

<p>Full sample published here: <a href="https://github.com/pulumi/examples/tree/master/azure-cs-botservice" target="_blank">https://github.com/pulumi/examples/tree/master/azure-cs-botservice</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Direct Line Speech</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/10/direct-line-speech/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/10/direct-line-speech/</guid>
            <description>Anne Uumellmahaye voice bot using Azure Bot Service: Direct Line Speech Recreating Anne Uumellmahaye using AI from the film The Man with Two Brains. Spooktacular fun with the Azure Bot Service using the Direct Line Speech channel and the Microsoft Cognitive Speech SDK.
Architecture Technologies used  Azure Bot Service and Direct Line Channel Bot Framework Microsoft Cognitive Services  Dispatcher LUIS QnA Maker Speech SDK  Azure Functions Spotify API UWP Raspberry Pi running Windows 10 IoT Halloween head  Who&amp;rsquo;s Freddy?</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="anne-uumellmahaye-voice-bot-using-azure-bot-service-direct-line-speech">Anne Uumellmahaye voice bot using Azure Bot Service: Direct Line Speech</h2>

<p>Recreating Anne Uumellmahaye using AI from the film The Man with Two Brains.  Spooktacular fun with the Azure Bot Service using the Direct Line Speech channel and the Microsoft Cognitive Speech SDK.</p>

<p><video src="/video/2brains.mp4" controls></p>

<h2 id="architecture">Architecture</h2>

<p><img src="/img/2brains_architecture.jpg"></p>

<h2 id="technologies-used">Technologies used</h2>

<ul>
<li>Azure Bot Service and Direct Line Channel</li>
<li>Bot Framework</li>
<li>Microsoft Cognitive Services

<ul>
<li>Dispatcher</li>
<li>LUIS</li>
<li>QnA Maker</li>
<li>Speech SDK</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Azure Functions</li>
<li>Spotify API</li>
<li>UWP</li>
<li>Raspberry Pi running Windows 10 IoT</li>
<li>Halloween head</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="who-s-freddy">Who&rsquo;s Freddy?</h2>

<p>See <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton/2016/11/03/building-a-physical-bot-using-the-botframework-freddythefishbot-futuredecoded-2016/" target="_blank">Freddy the fish</a></p>

<h2 id="resources">Resources</h2>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/bot-service-channel-connect-directlinespeech?view=azure-bot-service-4.0" target="_blank">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/bot-service-channel-connect-directlinespeech?view=azure-bot-service-4.0</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cognitive-services/speech-service/speech-sdk" target="_blank">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cognitive-services/speech-service/speech-sdk</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cognitive-services/speech-service/speech-synthesis-markup" target="_blank">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cognitive-services/speech-service/speech-synthesis-markup</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cognitive-services/speech-service/language-support#text-to-speech" target="_blank">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/cognitive-services/speech-service/language-support#text-to-speech</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/?view=azure-bot-service-4.0" target="_blank">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/?view=azure-bot-service-4.0</a></li>
<li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/bot-builder-tutorial-dispatch?view=azure-bot-service-4.0&amp;tabs=cs" target="_blank">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/bot-service/bot-builder-tutorial-dispatch?view=azure-bot-service-4.0&amp;tabs=cs</a></li>
<li><a href="https://developer.spotify.com/" target="_blank">https://developer.spotify.com/</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Home Automation</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/05/home-automation/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 19:49:05 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/05/home-automation/</guid>
            <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting/playing with home automation for a while now, specifically SmartThings and their development environment. At first I was overwhelmed by it all as it seemed a steep learning curve, getting to grips with the Groovy IDE and terminology such as device handlers and SmartApps - but now it&amp;rsquo;s a labour of love.
First things first though, home automation is largely pointless, it&amp;rsquo;s un-necessary and will likely cause you more problems that it&amp;rsquo;s worth in the short term.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been experimenting/playing with home automation for a while now, specifically SmartThings and their development environment.  At first I was overwhelmed by it all as it seemed a steep learning curve, getting to grips with the Groovy IDE and terminology such as device handlers and SmartApps - but now it&rsquo;s a labour of love.</p>

<p>First things first though, home automation is largely pointless, it&rsquo;s un-necessary and will likely cause you more problems that it&rsquo;s worth in the short term.  However, from a developer and technology perspective - it&rsquo;s AWESOME.  You can spend literally hours configuring devices to trigger events and turn things on/off, dim or change colour of lights etc.  All at the expense of anyone else you live with, who will most likey hate it and just say &ldquo;really?&rdquo; when you&rsquo;ve finally got the postbox to make the lamp flash on/off.</p>

<p>The first smart device on the SmartThings ecosystem I acquired was a Samsung Smart Fridge.  As well as a speaker, this also has builtin sensors that report it&rsquo;s running temperature, how much energy it&rsquo;s using and whether either of the fridge/freezer doors are open/closed.  It also came with an ice dispenser, so my first challenge was to see if the sensors reported if it was dispensing ice or not (it doesn&rsquo;t).  This is where you head over to the SmartThings Live Logging feature to watch all the activity within your home automation graph.  So the fall-back plan was to play &ldquo;Ice Ice Baby&rdquo; by Vanilla Ice whenever the freezer door was opened.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m an avid Spotify user and subscribe to the Premium service, this give me access to Spotify Connect - allowing me to target individual playback devices.  Crucially, Spotify has an API that allows you to control what music track gets played and on what device as well as controlling things such as the volume.  So the next challenge was how to invoke the Spotify API from SmartThings.  I initially thought about invoking it directly from a custom SmartApp, however this would have involved a fair amount of code in Groovy and I didn&rsquo;t want to write sluggish code that was going to grind other SmartApps down or timeout.  Instead I went with a server-side approach, creating a lighter weight SmartApp that invokes an Azure Function which does the grunt work - automating Spotify via the API.  To make life even easier, I discovered a nuget package by Jonas Dellinger that wraps the Spotify API into a simple SDK.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve had some fun (and tears) with this project, but it&rsquo;s amazing what automation scenarios you can achieve.  For instance - I now have a &ldquo;Game&rdquo; mode for the entire house.  Using a little device from the team at <a href="https://konnected.io" target="_blank">https://konnected.io</a> I&rsquo;ve been able to convert the existing alarm sensors around the house into SmartThings sensors.  So, not only can I trigger different music from different sensors, I can choose where the music gets played, what lights to flash and so on ;)</p>

<p>The full source code is available here: <a href="https://github.com/daltskin/ST-HomeAutomation" target="_blank">https://github.com/daltskin/ST-HomeAutomation</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>New Home</title>
            <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/04/new-home/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 16:44:23 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2019/04/new-home/</guid>
            <description>Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved my online home from https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton to here. Moving my site to Hugo using a static content builder will hopefully mean that I can blog more often, and now that I&amp;rsquo;m outside the blogs.msdn.microsoft.com domain I can write and share other technical articles or things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with.
So speaking of which, leads me to my upcoming next post about Home Automation&amp;hellip;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, I&rsquo;ve moved my online home from <a href="https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton" target="_blank">https://blogs.msdn.microsoft.com/jamiedalton</a> to here.  Moving my site to Hugo using a static content builder will hopefully mean that I can blog more often, and now that I&rsquo;m outside the blogs.msdn.microsoft.com domain I can write and share other technical articles or things that I&rsquo;ve been working with.</p>

<p>So speaking of which, leads me to my upcoming next post about Home Automation&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
