<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lockdown on Hello_world</title>
    <link>https://jamied.me/tags/lockdown/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lockdown on Hello_world</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 21:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamied.me/tags/lockdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tamiya Wild Willy WR02 - Lockdown project</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/04/tamiya-wild-willy-wr02-lockdown-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/04/tamiya-wild-willy-wr02-lockdown-project/</guid>
      <description>During lockdown I wanted something to do that didn&amp;rsquo;t involve a computer screen as I was spending crazy hours at the keyboard. I&amp;rsquo;ve (literally) home automated the shit out of my house already, so instead, returned to an old childhood hobby. As a kid I loved building and racing Tamiya RC cars, my first one was the entry level Tamiya Falcon, I then worked my way through some of their models with the Tamiya Hotshot being one of my favourites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving Lockdown</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/saving-lockdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 20:15:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2021/02/saving-lockdown/</guid>
      <description>Emergency surgery on the Xbox Kinect Phew! Tonight I saved lockdown in our household by fixing the Xbox Kinect :) Not many people seam to care or use the Kinect anymore, it was ahead of it&amp;rsquo;s time and never really got the traction it deserved. However, Just Dance 2021 (and previous versions) still supports it on the Xbox One.
Just Dance screen time is one I don&amp;rsquo;t mind the kids having, I&amp;rsquo;m an ex-breaker, so always happy to encourage dancing and listening to music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Home Multiplayer Bomb Disposal Game / Escape Room</title>
      <link>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 20:04:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamied.me/posts/2020/12/smart-home-multiplayer-bomb-disposal-game-/-escape-room/</guid>
      <description>About 18 months ago I shared some insight into some home automation I&amp;rsquo;d added that turned the whole house into a gaming zone. This has been pretty useful during the recent covid lockdown and provided much entertainment for the family. This post is to explain how it works.
Game objective Find and defuse the bomb without getting spotted. A baddie has hidden a bomb somewhere around the house, the bomb disposal team have been sent in to locate and defuse it - without activating any of the movement or contact sensors around the house.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>